

## **Summary of Qualifications**

Over 30 years of overall experience in IT, designing, developing many kinds of desktop, web and enterprise applications.

Clear understanding of Object Oriented Programming semantics and Design Patterns.

Excellent analytical ability to evaluate technologies, architectures, and product approach.

Experience in full development life cycle through OO Analysis/Design using UML, to implementation, testing, transition, support, and management activities: estimations, planning, development management, supervising projects.

Deep experience in major databases, including MySQL, MS SQL and Oracle DB and also in NoSQL databases such as REDIS, DynamoDB.

Wide experience in JDBC, Spring usage, Unit testing (JUnit, iMetter, Mock).

CI/CD pipelines.

Strong analytical and communications skills.

## Personal links & contacts

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yurishadrin

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/yurimix">https://github.com/yurimix</a>

https://github.com/nextlets

Email: <a href="mailto:ymshadrin@gmail.com">ymshadrin@gmail.com</a>

yshadrin@mail.ru

Skype: yuri.shadrin

Cell: +375 (29) 517-90-80

Location: Vitebsk, BY

## **Technical Skills**

Programming languages and technologies:

Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, C, C++ J2EE (JSP/Servlets, JSTL, GWT, Web Services, JDBC, JMX, JMS, JAXB, EJB, JNDI), AJAX, Design Patterns, UML, SQL, XML/XSL/XSLFO, HTML/CSS, TWAIN

*Operating Systems:* SCO Unix, Sun Solaris, Linux SuSE/Debian/Ubuntu/Mint, Windows 9x/NT/2K/XP/7/10

**Programming practices:** OOP, J2EE Design Patterns, Modeling, UML, Refactoring, ORM, GSA

*Frameworks and Libraries:* Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Struts, GWT, JDO, JUnit, jMeter, MAT, Log4j, Apache Commons, Swing, iText, Portlets, Apache POI, InversifyJS, GraphQL, GIT, GitLab, Jasmine, Jest

**Development Environments and Tools:** Eclipse, Idea, Microsoft Visual C++, Microsoft Project, Visual Studio Code

*Application/Web Servers:* Apache, Tomcat, JBoss, SunONE, WebLogic, Liferay, Express

**UML Modeling:** Rational Rose, Enterprise Architect, Visual Paradigm

Source Control: SVN, CVS, GIT

*CI/CD:* JIRA, BitBucket, Confluence, BambooCl, BambooCD

Dambooob

**RDBMS:** Oracle, MSSQL Server, MySQL, Aurora

Build Systems: Maven, Ant, LuntBuild, Jenkins,

Yarn

#### **Cloud Computing:**

AWS: CDK, CloudFormation, Aurora, ElastiCache (Redis), LoadBalancers, SSM, ECS (EC2, Fargate), Network and Security, S3, SNS, SQS, Lambda (Java, JS, TypeScript), StepFunctions, CloudWatch, Metrics, Alarms, etc.

## **Professional Experience**

#### Exadel www.exadel.com

08.2006 - 09.2023

#### **Wolters Kluwer Content Store**

2020 - 2023

Wolters Kluwer Content Store – low-level service for the Wolters Kluwer TaskFlow project provides storage, receiving and find data, including version control. The main storage is based on GIT (GitLab for remote and IsomorphicGit for local access), DynamoDB as a cache, AWS S3 for read-only replicas by regions. Written in TypeScript using Inversify, Express and GraphQL. Deployed on AWS using CDK.

**Position:** Senior Software Engineer

#### Main technologies:

- TypeScript, JS
- · Node.js, Docker
- · GraphQL, Rest API
- Git, GitLab
- DynamoDB
- AWS

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Development
- Requirements analysis
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

**Environment:** Linux Mint, GIT, GitLab, Visual Studio Code, TypeScript, Kibana, AWS: CDK, S3, lambda, DynamoDB, EFS, CloudWatch, SNS, SQS, CloudFormation. Sonar, BlackDuck, Sentry, Opsgenie.

#### **Wolters Kluwer REGENT**

2016 - 2020

REGENT – is a service based on micro-services architecture for managing and providing Wolters Kluwer CCH Trees (specially organized trees for legal, medical and other activities of WK clients). Written in Java using SpringBoot and TypeScript using Express. REDIS as a main data storage, AWS Aurora DB as an event storage. AWS S3 for replicas by regions. Deployed on AWS through CloudFormation templates.

**Position:** Senior Software Engineer

#### Main technologies:

- · Java, TypeScript, JS
- Spring Boot, Node.js, Docker
- · GRPC, Rest API

- ElastiCache (Redis), Aurora (MySQL)
- AWS

### Responsibilities included:

- Development
- · Requirements analysis
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

**Environment:** Ubuntu, JAVA, GRPC, jUnit, Eclipse, Idea, GIT, Maven, Docker, Logstash, Kibana, AWS: ECR, EC2, Lambda, Aurora, ElastiCache, Cloud Wath, SNS, Cloud Formation. Sonar, BlackDuck, Sentry, Opsgenie.

**AMC Reporting** 2015 - 2016

Position: Senior Software Engineer

AMC Networks Inc. (NASDAQ: AMCX) owns and operates several of the most popular and award-winning brands in cable television. AMC, IFC, SundanceTV, WE tv, and IFC Films produce and deliver distinctive, compelling and culturally relevant content that engages audiences across multiple platforms.

The project was dedicated to collecting and analyzing user activity on social networks such as FaceBook, Tumblr, Youtube, Instagram (and some others) in order to improve the content provided.

### Responsibilities included:

- Requirements analysis
- POC

API: Google, Youtube, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, WIKI, Tumblr.

**Environment:** Windows 7, Ubuntu, Android, JAVA, ¡Unit, Eclipse, Idea, GIT, Maven.

**SAIFE** 2014 - 2015

SAIFE is a patented, validated, software-only security platform that provides trusted routing for any endpoint, across any network, regardless of infrastructure. SAIFE uses its cloud-based network to create secure tunnels through the Internet in which the privacy and integrity of all traffic is assured.

**Position:** Senior Software Engineer

#### Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Bug fixing
- Deployment

**Environment:** Windows 7, Ubuntu, Android, JAVA, jUnit, Eclipse, Idea, GIT, Maven.

**EMC Veo One** 2012 - 2014

Veo One - the next generation of the information system of TD Ameritrade which is targeted to informational support of financial operations of their clients.

Position: Lead Software Engineer

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Backend development
- Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

**Environment:** Windows 7, Linux, JAVA, Spring, Spring MVC, Spring Remoting, Spring Batch, Spring JDBC, GSA, JavaScript, Angular, XML (and technologies for XML processing), jUnit, Eclipse, GIT, SVN, Maven, Ant, MS SQL, GSA, Oracle Coherence.

#### Wolters Kluwer PWI

2008 - 2012

Wolters Kluwer PWI (Portlet Web Interface), also known as Vesta.

PWI – it is a Web client with a rich interface of any search engine based on WK OSA technology. OSA - it is a multi-platform implementation of ODATA, PWI uses OSA as a library. One of PWI's contractors is Global Atlas. PWI is based on Portlet technology using Spring MVC.

**Position:** Lead Software Engineer

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Developers team management
- Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing
- · Deployment and load testing

**Environment:** Windows 2003, Windows XP, Windows 7, Linux, JAVA, Portlet API, Spring, Spring Portlet MVC, JSP, Servlets, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, BackBone, AJAX, JMS, XML (and technologies for processing), jUnit, Eclipse, CVS, SVN, Maven, Ant, Weblogic, Liferay on jBoss, Liferay on Tomcat, MS SQL, MySQL, GWT, CXF.

#### **Wolters Kluwer Cobalt**

2007 - 2008

Cobalt – it is a Web Service of Mantle. Cobalt provides Mantle's functions via Web Services. It is used in some clients which were designed and implemented by Wolters Kluwer.

Position: Lead Software Engineer

#### Responsibilities included:

- · Developers team management
- · Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing, deployment and load testing

**Environment:** Windows 2000, Windows XP, JAVA, Servlets, jUnit, Eclipse, CVS, Maven, Ant, Weblogic, AXIS.

#### **Wolters Kluwer Mantle**

2006 - 2007

Mantle - it is a business layer of Wolters Kluwer Global Atlas search engine. Mantle provides some additional functionality as compared with traditional search engines such as storing and access to personal data of users, their previous searches, collection of documents and so on.

**Position:** Senior Software Engineer

### Responsibilities included:

- Requirements analysis
- Documentation preparing
- Architecture design
- Bug fixing
- Deployment and load testing

**Environment:** Windows 2000, Windows XP, JAVA, J2EE, Spring, jUnit, Eclipse, CVS, Maven, Ant, Weblogic, MS SQL, MySQL.

Isida-Informatica www.isida.by

02.1994 - 08.2006

## The International festival of arts «Slavianski Bazaar in Vitebsk»

Information system of Art Festival.

**Position:** Senior Software Engineer

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Development
- Developers team management
- Communication with the customer
- Maintenance during the festival

**Environment:** Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, jUnit.

#### Archive of electronic documents

Archive of electronic documents ZAGS, St. Petersburg.

Creation of an archive of electronic documents based on scanned copies of originals since 1925, text recognition, a special life cycle for adding and checking details to relevant documents, search, maintenance.

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

**Environment:** Sun Solaris, MS Windows 2000/XP, JAVA, J2EE, SunONE, Oracle, TWAIN, ActiveX, Struts, jUnit, CVS, Canon broaching scanners.

## System of registration of electronic documents

System of registration of electronic documents, GBR, St. Petersburg.

The project solves the following issues: create an electronic archive of all documents related to the reality of St. Petersburg, search, reports and service of clients.

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

**Environment:** Sun Solaris, MS Windows 2000/XP, JAVA, J2EE, SunONE, Oracle, TWAIN, ActiveX, Struts, jUnit, CVS, BookScanner Codak.

## **Document Management System NBRB**

Document Management System of NB RB, Minsk

The forward project of the ISIDA Company in Belarus developed for the National Bank of the Republic Of Belarus. ISIDA DMS includes procedures of preparing, registration of documents, managing and control. A special technology for scanning paper documents based on a special TWAIN ActiveX component is used. Uses different reports in different formats such as HTML, PDF, MS Word and so on. It is used in the Central department and all regional departments of NB RB.

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

**Environment:** Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, MS SQL.

## **Document Management System LenEnergo**

Document Management System of LenEnergo, St. Petersburg. Project is based on ISIDA DMS for NB RB with some features.

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Development
- · Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

**Environment:** Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, Oracle.

## **Document Management System**

Document Management System of St. Petersburg Energy Company, based on ISIDA DMS for NB RB with some features.

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

**Environment:** Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, JAVA, ISIDA Application Server, Applet, ISIDA DBOX, PhotoShop, TWAIN, ActiveX, Oracle.

#### **ISIDA DBOX**

A database with special features such as terminological and based on graph of key-value pairs search, easy to deploy, use and maintenance. The database has a network interface and is used in a concurrent environment. It is used in some ISIDA projects including DMS,

Vitebsk Art Festival and some others. Database was developed from scratch using POSIX C and was fully portable between different operating systems (the forward system – Sun Solaris) including stored data.

Since 2002 DBOX database has been replaced by SQL Databases in main ISIDA projects.

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS Windows 95/97/2000/XP, POSIX C.

## **Email delivering system**

Email delivering system of normative documents of NB RB, Minsk Project was based on a special solution to deliver email which was used for bank communication at the time: PcoCarry from one side, and pre-version of ISIDA DMS from the second side.

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### **Responsibilities included:**

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: Sun Solaris, MS DOS, MS Windows 3.1, POSIX C.

## Megom plant, department of automatic control systems

07.1991 - 02.1994

**Position:** Software Engineer

#### Responsibilities included:

- Development
- Maintenance of the systems
- Architecture design
- Bug-fixing

Environment: MS-DOS, SCO UNIX, C, FoxBase for Unix, Informix.

# **Design Bureau of Automatic Control System, Vitebsk**

09.1990 - 07.1991

Automatic control systems for some factories of light industry

Position: Developer

### **Responsibilities included:**

- Development
- Post-production maintenance of the systems
- Bug-fixing

**Environment:** MS-DOS, FoxBase

## **Education**

**Vitebsk State Educational Institute, Vitebsk, Belarus** 

1989

Faculty of Physics and Mathematics.